# Mark Hayes

223 Genesee Marquette, MI 49855 T (906) 322-3097 mark.m.hayes1@gmail.com

Profile

I am a strategic and innovative thinker with 13 years of business development and management experience and 3 years of self-education in web design and development. I've completed 4 freelance projects in the past year. My strengths include creativity, tenacity, and resourcefulness.

Wed Development

# Freelance Developer Marquette, MI April 2016-Present

My freelance work has focused on self-education in all aspects of web development front and back end, with the underlying goal of becoming a technical project manager. Over the past 3 years I have spent my free time building knowledge in HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript. I've developed professional experience with several tools, libraries, and software packages required for modern web development including: Git and GitHub, NodeJS and Gulp, Wordpress, Square, and Sketch. I've recently started investigating ReactJS.

# Poets Pet Parlor Marquette, MI August 2016

#### Developer

Poets Pet Parlor was my first site. I build the site using HTML5, and CSS and hosted through GitHub Pages. At the client's request, I also integrated live Instagram feed "widget" that updates every 10 minutes. The site is fully responsive and optimized for mobile.

### Panara Imports Marquette, MI January 2017

#### Designer and Developer

I designed and built Panara Imports, which really gave me a great understanding of project management and client relationship from start to finish. I built a focused and minimal site to generate online traffic and bring business to the store, with plans for site expansion towards the end of 2017 into e-commerce through Square.

# Women's Center Marquette, MI September 2017

#### Designer and Developer

The Women's Center project was the largest project I've done and involved a full redesign, and content management system(CMS) and hosting transfer. I created the design and used Wordpress as the CMS to allow for client control and adjustments in the future. I worked directly with the client throughout the process to ensure that content and functionality were correct and that design fit the tone of their brand and mission.

# Derouin's Auto Shop Marquette, MI April 2018

#### Designer and Developer

Derouin's Auto Shop was my first paid job. The client was simply looking for a fresh look and to make the site mobile friendly. I created the design and built the site on Wordpress, allowing the client to make updates and perform common maintenance tasks.

# Mark Hayes

223 Genesee
Marquette, MI 49855
T (906) 322-3097
mark.m.hayes1@gmail.com

#### Professional Experience

#### Verizon Wireless Marquette, MI April 2016-Present

### Solutions Specialist

- Sales associate with direct customer interface. Providing tech support and trouble shooting for customer devices.
- Within 6 months of hiring, became the top sales rep in my store and top 20% of the Great Lakes Central District.
- Leader in new accounts and strategic phone adds for the Great Lakes Central District November and December 2017.

# Red Frog Events Chicago, IL 2012-2016

### Project Manager

- Managed and planned 30,000+ person events across the United States and around the world including Firefly Music Festival and Warrior Dash
- Negotiated contracts to establish long-term partnerships with major clients and vendors, including Game Face Media, Waste Management, and A-list Parking.
- Developed business plan for new regional event, Candy Cane Express, inaugural event garnered \$40,000 profit.
- Tasked with conceiving large-scale business ventures and events, where gross profit were to exceed 1 million in sales.
- Managed customer research and outreach for EventSprout online ticketing platform.

#### LSSU Recreation Center Sault Ste. Marie, MI 2008-2012

#### Facility Supervisor

- Supervised campus recreation facility utilized by entire student body and public.
- Wrote and implemented employee handbook in order to standardize best practices.
- Created positive data driven changes by analyzing visitor surveys and conducting user experience interviews.
- Administered program funding for campus organizations.

#### Starbucks Coffee Onalaska, WI 2006-2008

#### Store Manager

 Managed all store operations including customer and partner relations, employee scheduling, payroll and budgeting for 12 employees, 1 assistant manager and over \$60,000 in annual sales.

# Mark Hayes

223 Genesee Marquette, MI 49855 T (906) 322-3097 mark.m.hayes1@gmail.com

Education

LAKE SUPERIOR STATE UNIVERSITY, 01/08 - 05/12

Bachelor of Science in Parks and Recreation

GPA 3.89 - Dean's list, graduated Alpha Chi National Honors Society

Skills

Languages:

HTML5 (3 years) CSS (3 years) SASS (1 year) PHP (1 year) JavaScript (1 year) **Libraries and Tools:** 

Gulp (1 year) GitHub (2 years) Git (2 years) Wordpress (1 year) ReactJS (3 months) **Applications:** 

Terminal (3 years) macOS (5 years) Sublime Text (3 years) Sketch (3 years)

References

Sarah Doyle

General Manager Verizon Wireless sarahanndoyle@yahoo.com (906) 399-1709 Shana Kleinschmidt

Owner/Operator Poets Pet Parlor spavegli@gmail.com (906) 362-0374

Bugsy Sailor Owner/Operator U.P. Supply Company hello@bugsy.me (906) 395-7570 Tom Kita
Wizard of Web
Red Frog Events
tomkita00@gmail.com

(708) 846-9469

Beth Casady Executive Director Women's Center bcasady@miuplink.com

(906) 869-1237

Ashley Siebels

Art Director
Ladders
heyo@ashleysiebels.com

(612) 986-2585